<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>https://jakesimonds.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 14:27:37 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jakesimonds.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Auto-Journal</title>
      <link>https://jakesimonds.github.io/projects/autojournal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 14:14:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakesimonds.github.io/projects/autojournal/</guid>
      <description>Mostly just giving myself practice writing scripts, trying to automate straightforward &amp;amp; somewhat tedious tasks.
Was an opportunity to try a little bash (first time), also incorporated an API call to a weather service and another script that queries the local public library for when new books I&amp;rsquo;m interested in might drop (not sure how well that&amp;rsquo;ll work yet&amp;ndash;grabbed those upcoming book titles for testing purposes).
One kinda nice thing about journalling in a text document vs the cloud: a little harder (though still very possible) to get distracted since you&amp;rsquo;re not directly in the browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github Annotated</title>
      <link>https://jakesimonds.github.io/posts/github-annotated/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 12:21:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakesimonds.github.io/posts/github-annotated/</guid>
      <description>Github Annotated 1 I don&amp;rsquo;t remember making a github account, but I&amp;rsquo;m not surprised that I did. Summer of 2021 I made a lot of accounts with various services trying to see if this &amp;lsquo;get into tech&amp;rsquo; idea held any water. Requested the data from my sister&amp;rsquo;s netflix at one point. Filled out a form to make a twitter bot. Watched some TED talks. Read a lot of marketing materials from Boot Camps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://jakesimonds.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 12:56:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakesimonds.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>About Portland, ME-based software person. Can juggle up to five objects. CS Masters student at Northeastern (Roux Institute).
You can find some tutorials I made exploring images, latent space &amp;amp; jpg compression on youtube. I&amp;rsquo;m on bluesky and mastodon and other socials too. If you have a social internet thing that doesn&amp;rsquo;t suck I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear about it!
Very open to conversation/collaboration, remotely or in person here in Portland, ME.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://jakesimonds.github.io/projects_/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 12:56:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakesimonds.github.io/projects_/</guid>
      <description>Projects Not built yet. See github for now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I made this site</title>
      <link>https://jakesimonds.github.io/posts/how-i-made-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 12:21:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakesimonds.github.io/posts/how-i-made-it/</guid>
      <description>What it is Made with a framework called &amp;lsquo;Hugo,&amp;rsquo; and specifically using a theme called &amp;lsquo;paper.&amp;rsquo;
I heard about it on a youtube video. One of the comments, still there on the video as of 11/19/23, says: &amp;ldquo;Hugo is the back-end developer&amp;rsquo;s best friend for making front-ends.&amp;rdquo; That pretty much sold me.
It took me longer than I thought it would to get what I have today, and even this is less functionality-wise than my original ambitions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
