<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on </title>
    <link>https://jakesimonds.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 16:09:52 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jakesimonds.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dash Robot with Llama</title>
      <link>https://jakesimonds.github.io/posts/robotwllama/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 16:09:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakesimonds.github.io/posts/robotwllama/</guid>
      <description>What is it? Watching the short demo video (https://youtu.be/FoStVCW7-HY?si=YCHYhMVfsc7IoSCu) is probably the best quick way to see what&amp;rsquo;s going on, but to teach myself web development I made kinda the classic Web Development basic non-trivial website (with (super basic) authentication, a database, a front-end, a backend&amp;hellip;) but made it so you could log in, connect (locally) to a toy robot over bluetooth, and then drive it around.
You &amp;lsquo;drive it around&amp;rsquo; by just passing basic API calls (forward, left, right, back) to another program that passes those commands along to the robot itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Thoughts on XZ Backdoor Exploits</title>
      <link>https://jakesimonds.github.io/posts/xzbackdoor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 17:54:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakesimonds.github.io/posts/xzbackdoor/</guid>
      <description>April Fools!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!
I have nothing to add to the conversation. It&amp;rsquo;s very interesting, though!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Hot Takes for Posterity</title>
      <link>https://jakesimonds.github.io/posts/aihottakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 17:41:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakesimonds.github.io/posts/aihottakes/</guid>
      <description>Who am I? I&amp;rsquo;m a software engineer &amp;lt; 1 year into my career. I use ChatGPT a lot, sometimes maybe too much or beyond its purposes (working at the edge of your abilities &amp;gt; working at the edge of ChatGPT&amp;rsquo;s abilities).
Use-Cases I&amp;rsquo;m Not Ashamed Of Acronym hunting Say I&amp;rsquo;m reading a blogpost I found on hacker news and a paragraph or sentence mentions two or three acronyms I haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2023 Delights and Not So Delightfuls</title>
      <link>https://jakesimonds.github.io/posts/2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 18:51:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakesimonds.github.io/posts/2023/</guid>
      <description>Things I found Delightful &amp;amp; Not-So-Delightful in 2023 Year #2 of &amp;lsquo;getting into tech.&amp;rsquo; Feeling reflective, wanted to jot down some things that have brought me joy as well as a few things that just frustrated the hell out of me this year.
Delightful Linux Chromebook Oh boy is linux fun! Bought a chromebook with ubuntu off a friend, and it has slowly become my primary personal machine. Trackpad sucks, bluetooth headphones sometimes don&amp;rsquo;t connect great (delay or just terribly quality).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dumb Electronics</title>
      <link>https://jakesimonds.github.io/posts/electronics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 20:42:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakesimonds.github.io/posts/electronics/</guid>
      <description>This summer started picking up electric oddities and toys at the goodwill. Had some fun taking them apart, learning a bit (though less than you might think) about electrics, and occasionally tried some weird stuff. If you&amp;rsquo;re in Portland ME and want to borrow either the camera or the keyboards for projects or fun, or collaborate on other similar stuff, be in touch!
Camera The case.
The Camera
This is my iPhone&amp;rsquo;s perspective&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wordle Percentage Curiousity</title>
      <link>https://jakesimonds.github.io/posts/wordle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 10:20:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakesimonds.github.io/posts/wordle/</guid>
      <description>Did you know that the &amp;lsquo;Percentage&amp;rsquo; on your wordle stats is simply the number you&amp;rsquo;ve done successfully, over the total number of attempts rounded to the nearest integer? So 198/199 = 99.4975ish, rounds down to 99.
While 199/200 = 99.5, rounds up to 100.
I feel obligated to add: chasing this curiousity I cheated many times, by opening up a new browser and then continuing to guess until I knew I had the right word.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github Annotated</title>
      <link>https://jakesimonds.github.io/posts/github-annotated/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 12:21:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakesimonds.github.io/posts/github-annotated/</guid>
      <description>Github Annotated 1 I don&amp;rsquo;t remember making a github account, but I&amp;rsquo;m not surprised that I did. Summer of 2021 I made a lot of accounts with various services trying to see if this &amp;lsquo;get into tech&amp;rsquo; idea held any water. Requested the data from my sister&amp;rsquo;s netflix at one point. Filled out a form to make a twitter bot. Watched some TED talks. Read a lot of marketing materials from Boot Camps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I made this site</title>
      <link>https://jakesimonds.github.io/posts/how-i-made-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 12:21:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakesimonds.github.io/posts/how-i-made-it/</guid>
      <description>What it is Made with a framework called &amp;lsquo;Hugo,&amp;rsquo; and specifically using a theme called &amp;lsquo;paper.&amp;rsquo;
I heard about it on a youtube video. One of the comments, still there on the video as of 11/19/23, says: &amp;ldquo;Hugo is the back-end developer&amp;rsquo;s best friend for making front-ends.&amp;rdquo; That pretty much sold me.
It took me longer than I thought it would to get what I have today, and even this is less functionality-wise than my original ambitions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
